- Captain, what's this town called?
- Puerto Miguel.
- Is it alive?
- It's asleep.
When the sun falls people
will get up. They call it a siesta.
Do we have to siesta here
for 4 weeks?
4, 5, 6...
- Take that long to fix an engine?
- Not me. The engineer.
I didn't make the steamboat,
I just operate one.
- Captain, wait!
- Every mother's son...
...is picking up gold by the fistful
in California...
...and I'm marooned in a Mexican
village called Pu...
- What did he call it?
- Puerto Miguel.
Puerto Miguel.
- But what can we do about it?
- Nothing.
- They must have some alcohol.
- I think so.
There we are.
It's a funny thing.
I know everybody on board except you.
I don't know anything about you.
- Your called Hooker and that's it.
- That's it.
That kid thinks he knows you
from Texas, but he can't remember.
Then it couldn't have been much.
And even if it was,
it wouldn't be any of my business.
I can't see how.
Being a professional gambler,
I like to know the people I meet...
...because I might play them sometime.
That's what makes me so inquisitive.
- That's natural.
- I'm also a kind of poet...
...and all kinds of people
interest me.
- That makes sense.
- I see what I can get out of them,
...either their money or their
character, or both.
You've heard of &quot;getting blood
out of a stone&quot;, haven't you?
- Yeah.
- That's what I'm getting out of you.
Two drinks.
This is the way my luck's running.
I can speak two languages,
...but I'm in a country
that isn't one of them.
I found that pretty women
speak the same language everywhere.
- What about the ugly ones?
- I never listened.
It's not as bad as I thought it'd be.
It's worse.
Somebody once said:
&quot;Believe nothing a woman says,
...but believe everything she sings&quot;.
- Who said that?
- Me.
What's the trouble with him?
What's he saying?
He disliked the way that man
was looking at his girl.
You see we want to be peaceful
and friendly.
We may be here
for quite a while.
I can handle myself.
- I'm sure of it.
- You think not?
- He just said &quot;he was sure of it&quot;.
- Relax, Daly.
It may not be as bad as you think.
We can fish in the mornings,
get drunk in the afternoons...
...and we can play cards at night.
- You might even get lucky.
- Like catching lighting in a bottle.
Fiske, you know what you can do
with a deck of cards?
You can tell my fortune.
Anything you like.
The Red Queen.
That means that...
What do you know.
- What's she saying?
- She's got a mine.
Her husband is trapped in a cave-in.
She wants help to get him out.
- She'll pay 1,000 dollars a man.
- There ain't a man at the bar.
Did you hear what I said?
Did you understand?
He just told us.
I offered them a thousand a piece.
I'll double it for any of you
if you'll help.
A man is lying out there hurt,
maybe dying. An American.
- If that isn't enough...
- The price is right.
- But, why is it so high?
- Is a man's life too high a price?
I didn't put the price on it,
you did.
I don't know what to do
or what to say.
- I've got to get help or he'll die.
- Lady, won't you sit down?
Why will none of them go
even for so much money?
None of them will go out there.
They're afraid of the Indians.
Are you?
You don't look afraid.
Ma'am, the thing I'm afraid off
still hasn't been found.
He says only fools go up there.
He must be one.
He's going with her.
- You said 2,000 dollars?
- You've got it in your hand.
- All right, I'll go.
- 2,000 for each of the rest of you.
You?
Madam, I can live anywhere
in the world for 6 weeks,
...but alone in this town.
Meet me in an hour
at the blacksmith's shop.
I'd like for one of you
to come with me now.
You.
- Are we lost?
- No.
We pass the face of that cliff.